Guide to the Arthur Lee Loeb papers M1590
Dept. of Special Collections & University Archives
- Series 3: Faculty/Coursework
  - VES 175 & 176 Shopping Period originals (Box 54, Folder 11)
  - Golden Section (Box 54, Folder 12)
  - VES 175 Fall 1997-98 (Box 54, Folder 13)
  - VES 176 Spring 1998 (Box 54, Folder 14)
  - Class Handouts (Box 54, Folder 15)
  - Academic materials related to Chemistry & Crystals (Box 54, Folder 16)
  - VES receipts Fall 1988 (Box 55, Folder 1)
  - VES 176 CUE ratings 1988 & 1989 (Box 55, Folder 2)
  - VES 175 CUE signup lists Fall 1989 (Box 55, Folder 3)
  - VES 175 CUE ratings 1989 (Box 55, Folder 4)
  - VES 175 receipts, budget Fall 1989 (Box 55, Folder 5)
  - VES 175 Fall 1989 homework assignments (Box 55, Folder 6)
  - VES 175 Fall 1989 class lists, grading (Box 55, Folder 7)
  - VES 175 Spring 1990/91 homework (Box 55, Folder 8)
  - Course grading General, Dept. 1990/91 (Box 55, Folder 9)
  - VES 175 Spring 1991 class list + info, grade book (Box 55, Folder 10)
  - VES 175 CUE results 1991 (Box 55, Folder 11)
  - Design Science Bibliography 1991 (Box 55, Folder 12)
  - VES 175 & 176 old assignments (Box 55, Folder 13)
  - VES 175 Spring 1992 class lists + correspondence (Box 55, Folder 14)
  - VES 176 Fall 1992 (Box 55, Folder 15)
  - Teaching Collection Forms (Box 55, Folder 16)
  - Library Guide and COOP book order forms (Box 55, Folder 17)
  - Photocopies of Escher Designs (Box 55, Folder 18)
  - Course Evaluation Guide 1993-94 (Box 55, Volume 1)
  - Design Science Conference mailing list (Half-box 84, Folder 1)
  - Design Science Annual Reports 1980-81, 1981-82 (Half-box 84, Folder 2)
  - Design Science miscellaneous (Half-box 84, Folder 3)
  - Design Science 25th Anniversary (Half-box 84, Folder 4)
  - Design Science Bibliography (Half-box 84, Folder 5)
  - Design Science talk by A. Loeb Suzdal, Russia June 1999 (Half-box 84, Folder 6)
  - Proposal: Design Revolution '76 - The World Game (Half-box 84, Folder 7)
  - Curriculum Vitae Arthur L. Loeb (Box 86, Folder 1)
  - Arthur Loeb biographical material (Box 86, Folder 2)
  - Crystograph patent (Box 86, Folder 3)
  - Arthur Loeb faculty miscellaneous (Box 86, Folder 4)
  - Loeb office miscellaneous (Box 86, Folder 5)
  - Sabbatical (Box 86, Folder 6)
  - Faculty appointments (Box 86, Folder 7)
  - Harvard: Yearly Reports (Box 86, Folder 8)
  - Harvard: CUE Course evals + AVS service requests (Box 86, Folder 9)
  - Math 110b Class notes & outline (Box 86, Folder 10)
  - MA DoE: Mass Curriculum Frameworks for Mathematics, Reveiw draft Oct. 1994 (Box 86, Folder 11)
  - MA DoE: Mass Curriculum Frameworks for Science & Technology, Reveiw draft Oct. 1994 (Box 86, Folder 12)
  - Scrap book given to Loeb on retirement (Flat-box 95, Volume 1)
- Series 4: M.C. Escher
  Series 4, M.C. Escher, is primarily related to Loeb's collaborations with Escher and contains correspondence with Escher and his widow, books, exhibition announcements, postcards, and some of Loeb’s essays on Escher.
  - M.C.E. 1960 (Box 79, Folder 1)
  - M.C.E. 1961 (Box 79, Folder 2)
  - M.C.E. 1962 (Box 79, Folder 3)
  - M.C.E. 1963 (Box 79, Folder 4)
  - M.C.E. 1964 (Box 79, Folder 5)
  - M.C.E. 1965 (Box 79, Folder 6)
  - M.C.E. 1966 (Box 79, Folder 7)
  - M.C.E. 1967 (Box 79, Folder 8)
  - M.C.E. 1968 (Box 79, Folder 9)
  - M.C.E. 1969 (Box 79, Folder 10)
  - M.C.E. 1970 (Box 79, Folder 11)
  - M.C.E. 1971 (Box 79, Folder 12)
  - George Escher (Box 79, Folder 13)
  - Misc. Corr 1 (Box 79, Folder 14)
  - Misc. Corr 2 (Box 79, Folder 15)
  - Photo Baaru September 1958 (Box 79, Folder 16)
  - Escher Post cards & exhibit cards (Box 79, Folder 17)
  - Newspaper Clippings, M.C. Escher (Box 79, Folder 18)
  - Escher exhibition catalogs (1 of 2) (Box 79, Folder 19)
  - Escher exhibition catalogs (2 of 2) (Box 79, Folder 20)
  - Escher work by A. Loeb (1 floppy disc) (Box 79, Folder 21)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, A. Loeb re: M.C. Escher (Box 80, Folder 1)
  - M.C. Escher miscellaneous (Box 80, Folder 2)
  - Escher magazine articles, reprints, book reviews (Box 80, Folder 3)
  - Escher prints for Wiley monograph (Box 80, Folder 4)
  - Grafiek En Tekeningen inscribed to Loeb, 1964 (Box 106, Folder 12)
- Series 5: Miscellaneous
  Series 5, Miscellaneous, contains punch cards (alphabetical list of references), notebooks from Legdemont Labs, files related to dance (see also "medieval misc." in Series 6), Loeb's memorial, notes of Bucky Fuller, video interview with Loeb on survivors on the holocaust, etc.
  - Punch cards: used for note taking (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Punch cards: Alpha references (1 of 9) (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Punch cards: Alpha references (2 of 9) (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Punch cards: Alpha references (3 of 9) (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Punch cards: Alpha references (4 of 9) (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Punch cards: Alpha references (5 of 9) (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Punch cards: Alpha references (6 of 9) (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Punch cards: Alpha references (7 of 9) (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Punch cards: Alpha references (8 of 9) (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Punch cards: Alpha references (9 of 9) (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Punch cards: supplies (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Ledgemont Lab notebooks (Box 27, Volume 1)
  - Ledgemont Lab notebooks (Box 27, Volume 2)
  - Ledgemont Lab notebooks (Box 27, Volume 3)
  - Dance (1 of 3) (Box 83, Folder 1)
  - Dance (2 of 3) (Box 83, Folder 2)
  - Dance (3 of 3) (Box 83, Folder 3)
  - Symmetries in Dance, Music (Box 83, Folder 4)
  - Dances created by A. Loeb (1 of 2) (Box 83, Folder 5)
  - Dances created by A. Loeb (2 of 2) (Box 83, Folder 6)
  - Ancestry trees (Box 83, Folder 7)
  - Burgundy material (Box 83, Folder 8)
  - Memorials & Letters on the death of Loeb (Half-box 87, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous photos (Half-box 87, Folder 2)
  - "Random Items" - scientific memos of interest #1-#3 (Half-box 87, Folder 3)
  - miscellaneous notecards (Half-box 87, Folder 4)
  - Harvard Magazine: The Polyhedral Arthur Loeb March/April 1982 (Half-box 87, Folder 5)
  - R.B. Fuller: address by Fuller at Ledgemont Laboratories Oct. 15, 1964 (Box 94, Folder 1)
  - R.B. Fuller: NASA speech with MS notations (Box 94, Folder 2)
  - R.B. Fuller: report on second year as "World Fellow in Residence" (Box 94, Folder 3)
  - R.B. Fuller: "Buckminster Fuller Retrospective" - photocopy (Box 94, Folder 4)
  - R.B. Fuller: "Dymaxion Comprehensive System" - photocopy of TS (Box 94, Folder 5)
  - R.B. Fuller: Centenary Forum at MIT (Box 94, Folder 6)
  - R.B. Fuller: Centennial Forum, Cambridge UK November 1995 (Box 94, Folder 7)
  - R.B. Fuller: Death of Fuller (Box 94, Folder 8)
  - R.B. Fuller: commemorative stamp correspondence (Box 94, Folder 9)
  - R.B. Fuller: Loeb's podium copy of speech "Fuller versus the Irrational" (Box 94, Folder 10)
  - Philomorph September 22, 2002 (3 copies) (Box 98, Videotapes 1-3)
  - Survivors of the Shoah + Arthur Loeb interview (2 copies) (Box 98, Videotapes 4-5)
  - Race for the Buckyball (Box 98, Videotape 6)
  - Endeavor by Lenard T. Giggins et al. (Box 98, Videotape 7)
  - Evident-Improbable (Soviet TV program featuring A. Loeb talk at Symmetry of Structure symposium. Budapest 1989 (Box 98, Videotape 8)
  - Memorial Service September 23, 2002 (Box 98, Videotape 9)
  - In Memorium: Arthur Loeb (Box 98)
  - Moeder (Box 98)
  - Crystallography miscellaneous (Box 99, Folder 1)
  - Textile Museum (Box 99, Folder 2)
  - Applicants for Teaching Position (Box 99, Folder 3)
  - Teaching Alums (Box 99, Folder 4)
  - Alums notes/letters (Box 99, Folder 5)
  - Colleagues notes/letters (Box 99, Folder 6)
  - Photos/cards (Box 99, Folder 7)
  - Geoff Binney (Box 99, Folder 8)
  - Books & articles & products to acquire (Box 99, Folder 9)
  - Gaia Tech (Box 99, Folder 10)
  - Rhombics (Box 99, Folder 11)
  - Loeb: symmetry figures (Box 99, Folder 12)
  - Glass slides + glass plate (Oversize 100, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous cards, negatives (Oversize 100, Folder 2)
  - Ralph Casale (Oversize 100, Folder 3)
  - "The Structure of Symmetry in Design" - sample copy by Victoria Chave (Oversize 100, Folder 4)
  - "Abstract Mathematics Communicated Through Visualization" photocopy (Oversize 100, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous art work (Oversize 100, Folder 6)
  - Diplomas, certificates, & awards (Oversize 100, Folder 7)
  - Arthur's notes - overhead projector slides (Oversize 100, Folder 8)
  - Galley proof of "Symmetry" by Loeb (Oversize 100, Folder 9)
  - 5x8 card files (Card-box 101)
  - Computer punch card tool (Card-box 102, Object 1)
  - Fullerene model made from plastic and wire (Card-box 102, Model 1)
  - Collage, unknown artist, no date (Box 106, Folder 10)
  - radioprogramma EEN UUR ISCHA; uitgezonden 24 februari 1987; Ischa in gesprek met ELI ASSER over zijn leven en zijn werk (his life and work). (Carton 109)
- Series 6: General files
  Series 6, General Files, relate to Loeb's varied interests such as medieval era, art, and contain photographs of Loeb and his work. The folders titled “medieval misc.” contain files on medieval and renaissance dances. Loeb was interested in the symmetry and repeating patterns.
  - AAAS 2000 Symposium correspondence (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - AAAS 2000 Symposium conference material (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Art shows, announcements, articles, etc. (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Association of Harvard Chemists (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence re: Art, etc. (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Catalogs, educational materials (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Cathles, Prof. Lawrence M. (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Chen, Joseph (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - AANS Conference 1994 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Design Science Symposium 1980 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Education for the 21st Century 10/28/1987-10/31/1987 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Conferences/Programs (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Mathematics & Art conference Suzdal, Russia 1996 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - miscellaneous conference papers (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Conference on Polyhedra 1984, Smith College (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Proceedings of the Royal Netherlands Academy (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Structural Morphology Conference, Delft Aug. 2000 (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - University of Pennsylvania Class of 1944 50th Reunion (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Computer Components & Systems Group (1 of 2) (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Computer Components & Systems Group (2 of 2) (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Computer & Calculator - advertising material (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Conference on communication of 2D & 3D patterns and concepts (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Coolidge Center (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - CORE Program report (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Games magazine V.6, no. 1 Jan/Feb 1982 (Islamic art article) (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Geometry related products & brochures (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Visualizing Higher Dimensions, Flatland 1984, etc. (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - International Communication Association (1 of 3) (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - International Communication Association (2 of 3) (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - International Communication Association (3 of 3) (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Journal for Research in Science Teaching (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Journal of Colloid Science (draft article) (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Journal of Solid State Chemistry (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - layoff, job search, etc. (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - MAST Teaching System 1964 (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Mathematical Association of America (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - The Mathematics Teacher (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Medieval misc. (1 of 4) (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Medieval misc. (2 of 4) (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Medieval misc. (3 of 4) (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Medieval misc. (4 of 4) (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Metaloglass Inc. (catalogs) (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - MIT Press: Todd Siler (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - MIT Press: catalogs (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - MIT Press: misc. materials (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - MIT:Materials Science & Engineering (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - MIT: research reports, budgets (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - MIT:Crystallography Seminar 1961-1962 (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - MIT:Technology Review (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - Loeb kinship graphs (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - miscellaneous, Marchant conference (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - misc. newsletters, ephemera (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - National Trust for Historic Preservation (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - National Endowment for the Humanities (NEH) (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Nieuwenhuysen (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Remembrances of Eric Haughton (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Renaissance Universal journal (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Thesis, Uri Feldman (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - Tozier Fund (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - Golden Door Awards 1987 (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - Illustration boards (Box 73, Folders 1-5)
  - Illustration boards (Box 74, Folders 1-4)
  - Illustration boards (Box 75, Folders 1-3)
  - Photos: Figures for TR-289 (Box 76, Folder 1)
  - Photos: A.L. Loeb Exhibit (Box 76, Folder 2)
  - Photos: Negatives & Masters (Box 76, Folder 3)
  - Photos: Stacking Functions (Box 76, Folder 4)
  - Photos: Escher Prints (Box 76, Folder 5)
  - Photos: teaching (Box 76, Folder 6)
  - Photos: Domuledra negative (Box 76, Folder 7)
  - Photos: Moduledra (Box 76, Folder 8)
  - Photos: Color symmetry problem (Box 76, Folder 9)
  - Photos: Color and Symmetry illustrations (Box 76, Folder 10)
  - Photos: Studio for Spatial Order - negatives (Box 76, Folder 11)
  - Photos: Masters of figures for Leonardo (Box 76, Folder 12)
  - Photos: Exhibit photos - trimmed (Box 76, Folder 13)
  - Photos: Photo file from Prof. Victor Klee, Univ. of Washington (Box 77, Folder 1)
  - Photos: Domes & Models (Box 77, Folder 2)
  - Photos: Prints "Il Contrapasso..." (Box 77, Folder 3)
  - Photos: IBM foils (Box 77, Folder 4)
  - Photos: Illustrations for Symmetry & Modularity (Box 77, Folder 5)
  - Photos: Hypergraphics 1984 talk (Box 77, Folder 6)
  - Photos: Holly Aldeman-Armitage (Box 77, Folder 7)
  - Photos: Loeb teaching photos (1 of 3) (Box 77, Folder 8)
  - Photos: Loeb teaching photos (2 of 3) (Box 77, Folder 9)
  - Photos: Loeb teaching photos (3 of 3) (Box 77, Folder 10)
  - Photos: Deli Bloembergen reproductions (Box 77, Folder 11)
  - Photos: Vector Equilibrium Synergy (Box 77, Folder 12)
  - Photos: Crystograph Photos & Schematics (Box 77, Folder 13)
  - Photos: Loeb models (Box 78, Folder 1)
  - Photos: template patterns (Box 78, Folder 2)
  - Photos: plastic sheet models (Box 78, Folder 3)
  - Photos: Ledgemont Labs schematics of models (Box 78, Folder 4)
  - Photos: Symmetry slide presentation (Box 78, Folder 5)
  - Photos: Unwrapping the Cube - unused prints for Leonardo (Box 78, Folder 6)
  - Photos: Models & student work (Box 78, Folder 7)
  - Photos: Coursework VS130 1967 (Box 78, Folder 8)
  - Photos: student work (Box 78, Folder 9)
  - Photos: misc. photos of Loeb (Box 78, Folder 10)
  - IBM: NIAL & Q'NIAL program language (1 of 2) (Box 82, Folder 1)
  - IBM: NIAL & Q'NIAL program language (2 of 2) (Box 82, Folder 2)
  - IBM: Kinship program (Box 82, Folder 3)
  - Kinship program (Box 82, Folder 4)
  - IBM: miscellaneous (Box 82, Folder 5)
  - Journal of Interdisciplinary History: Kinship Graphs (Box 82, Folder 6)
  - Programmed Instruction: Advanced Symmetry Concepts in Grade 6 by Jim Milliren (Box 82, Folder 7)
  - Journal of Pragrammed Instruction: Programmed use of physical models (Box 82, Folder 8)
  - MIT Summer Program on Switching Circuits June 18-29, 1956 (Box 85, Folder 1)
  - Papers on Switching Circuits, Network Switching, etc. (Box 85, Folder 2)
  - MIT Summer Program on Material Science Jun 11-23, 1961 (Box 85, Folder 3)
  - Harvard: Developing Discussion Leadership Skills seminar Fall 1987 (Box 85, Folder 4)
  - Office for the Arts: Learning from Performers (Box 85, Folder 5)
  - Office for the Arts: Learning from Performers, press releases (Box 85, Folder 6)
  - Institute of Contemporary Arts (Box 85, Folder 7)
  - Jewish Community Center Art & Exhibits, Harrisburg, PA (Box 85, Folder 8)
  - Clippings re: R.B. Fuller (Box 96, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous clippings/reviews/publication catalogs re: R.B. Fuller (Box 96, Folder 2)
  - Crystograph (Box 96, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous studio art work & clippings (Box 96, Folder 4)
  - "Can a Renaissance Man Survive in a Competitive Culture" Speech version (Box 96, Folder 5)
  - Loeb early academic work (Box 96, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence re: teaching and publishing (Box 97, Folder 1)
  - Ealing: Bubble Model of a Crystal (Box 97, Folder 2)
  - Stilgoe, John: photocopies/reprints of articles (Box 97, Folder 3)
  - Pennsylvannia Gazette April 1974 (Box 97, Folder 4)
  - University of Pennsylvannia (Box 97, Folder 5)
  - Memos: Thin Films research (Box 97, Folder 6)
  - Ingber, Donald Elliot - dissertation (Box 97, Folder 7)
  - Eisenstein, Jane "Rotations & Notations" (Box 97, Folder 8)
  - Elizabeth Morrow School (Box 97, Folder 9)
  - Notes on slides illustrating the 17 plane diperiodic symmetry groups (Box 97, Folder 10)
- Series 7: Associations/Conferences/Bulletins
  Series 7, Associations/Conferences/Bulletins, contains materials primarily related to the American Crystallographic Association.
  - Academy of Management (Box 56, Folder 1)
  - American Association for the Advancement of Science (Box 56, Folder 2)
  - American Association of Physics Teachers (AAPT) - miscellaneous (Box 56, Folder 3)
  - American Association of Physics Teachers (AAPT) - Commission on College Physics (Box 56, Folder 4)
  - American Crystallographic Association 1967 (Box 56, Folder 5)
  - American Crystallographic Association 1968 (Box 56, Folder 6)
  - American Crystallographic Association 1969 (Box 56, Folder 7)
  - American Crystallographic Association 1971 (Box 56, Folder 8)
  - American Crystallographic Association 1972 (Box 56, Folder 9)
  - American Crystallographic Association 1973 (Box 57, Folder 1)
  - American Crystallographic Association 1974 (Box 57, Folder 2)
  - American Crystallographic Association 1975 (Box 57, Folder 3)
  - American Crystallographic Association 1977-1985 (Box 57, Folder 4)
  - American Crystallographic Association Annual Meetings 1988-1990 (Box 57, Folder 5)
  - American Institue of Chemists (Box 57, Folder 6)
  - American Institute of Physics (Box 57, Folder 7)
  - American Journal of Physics (Box 57, Folder 8)
  - American Journal of Physics: The Heisenberg Uncertainty Principal (Box 58, Folder 1)
  - American Mathematical Society (Box 58, Folder 2)
  - American Physical Society (Box 58, Folder 3)
  - American Physicists Association (Box 58, Folder 4)
  - American Society for Aesthetics (Box 58, Folder 5)
  - American Society for Engineering Education (Box 58, Folder 6)
  - The Amphographer - M.C. Escher Society (Box 58, Folder 7)
  - Conference: ARCHIMEDIA '72 (1972) (Box 58, Folder 8)
  - Association of Technical Professionals ATP newsletter (Box 58, Folder 9)
  - International Union of Crystallography Congress (1 of 2) (Box 58, Folder 10)
  - International Union of Crystallography Congress (2 of 2) (Box 58, Folder 11)
  - Transactions of the American Crystallographic Association (1) (Box 58, Folder 12)
  - Transactions of the American Crystallographic Association (2) (Box 59, Folder 1)
  - Directories - Crystallography (Box 59, Folder 2)
  - Directories - Chemistry & Crystallography (Box 59, Folder 3)
  - Ledgemont Symposium 1969 (1 of 2) (Box 59, Folder 4)
  - Ledgemont Symposium 1969 (2 of 2) (Box 59, Folder 5)
  - CEIDP conference (Box 93, Folder 1)
  - Sixth International Congress of Crystallographers: Rome 1963 (Box 93, Folder 2)
  - Fourth International Congress and Exhibition of ISIS Symmetry (Box 93, Folder 3)
  - Solid State Chemical Conference April 1967 (Box 93, Folder 4)
  - Space Structure Conference (Box 93, Folder 5)
  - Symposium: Symmetry of Structure Budapest 1989 (Box 93, Folder 6)
  - Stereology, International Society for (Box 93, Folder 7)
  - Kernforschungzentrum Karlsrue / Stereology Newsletter September 1973 (Box 93, Folder 8)
- Series 8: Academic Juvenalia
  Series 8, Academic Juvenalia, contains a diary from 1940, school notebooks, papers, textbooks, etc.
  - Loeb academic juvenalia 1 (Box 68, Folder 1)
  - Loeb academic juvenalia 2 (Box 68, Folder 2)
  - Loeb academic juvenalia 3 (Box 68, Folder 3)
  - Loeb academic juvenalia 4 (Box 68, Folder 4)
  - Loeb academic juvenalia 5 (Box 68, Folder 5)
  - Differential Equations class notes (Box 69, Folder 1)
  - Chemistry 28A class notes (Box 69, Folder 2)
  - Chemistry 104 notes (Box 69, Folder 3)
  - Chemistry 109 - Organic Chemistry class notes (Box 69, Folder 4)
  - Colloidal Chemistry class notes (Box 69, Folder 5)
  - Physics 4b workbook (Box 69, Folder 6)
  - MIT: Electrical Engineering 6.08 Lecture notes, problem sets (1 of 2) (Box 69, Folder 7)
  - MIT: Electrical Engineering 6.08 Lecture notes, problem sets (2 of 2) (Box 69, Folder 8)
  - Diary: Netherlands 1940 MS (Box 70, Folder 1)
  - School work: English papers & quizes (Box 70, Folder 2)
  - Ph.D Thesis (Box 70, Folder 3)
  - Research notebook for Ph. D thesis (Box 70, Folder 4)
  - Academic notebook (Box 71, Volume 1)
  - Academic notebook (Box 71, Volume 2)
  - Academic notebook (Box 71, Volume 3)
  - Academic notebook (Box 71, Volume 4)
  - Academic notebook (Box 71, Volume 5)
  - Academic notebook (Box 72, Volume 1)
  - Academic notebook (Box 72, Volume 2)
  - Academic notebook (Box 72, Volume 3)
  - Academic notebook (Box 72, Volume 4)
  - Academic notebook (Box 72, Volume 5)
  - Academic notebook (Box 72, Volume 6)
  - College entrance examination board 1940 (Box 72, Folder 7)
  - misc. notebooks (Box 72, Folder 8)
  - textbooks (Box 104, Box 103)
    Most textbooks have Loeb’s name written inside, as well as some inserted notes, annotations, bookplates, and book covers.
    Badger, Walter L. and Warren L. McCabe. Elements of Chemical Engineering. New York: McGraw-Hill, 1936.
    Bokhorst, S.C. Leerboek Der Scheikunde. Ten Dienste Van Hogere Burgerscholen, Gymnasia En Lycea. Deel IA. Groningen: J.B. Wolters, 1938.
    Bokhorst, S.C. Leerboek Der Scheikunde. Ten Dienste Van Hogere Burgerscholen, Gymnasia En Lycea. Deel IB. Groningen: J.B. Wolters, 1938.
    Derksen, H.A and G.L.N.H. de Laive. Leerboek der Beschrijvende Meetkunde. Zutphen: W.J. Thieme, 1910.
    Engelder, Carl J. A Textbook of Qualitative Analysis. 2nd ed. New York: John Wiley & Sons, 1933.
    Fisher, Harry L. Laboratory Manual of Organic Chemistry. 4th ed. New York: John Wiley & Sons, 1938.
    Harvard University Chemical Laboratories. Chemistry A Laboratory Experiments. 1944.
    Hougen, O.A. and K.M. Watson. Industrial Chemical Calculations. The application of Physico-Chemical Principles and Data to Problems of Industry. 2nd ed. New York: John Wiley & Sons, 1936.
    Jacobsen, R. and M. Engers. Leerboek Der Oude Geschiedenis. Voor Gymnasia En Lycea. Rotterdam: W.L. Brusse, 1930.
    Jordan, Harvey H. and Hoelscher, Randolph P. Engineering Drawing. 3rd ed. New York: John Wiley & Sons, 1935.
    Kicks, H.J. Introductory Radio: Theory and Servicing. New York: McGraw-Hill, 1949.
    Mellon, M.G. Chemical Publications: Their Nature And Use. New York: McGraw-Hill, 1940.
    Shriner, Ralph L. and Reynold C. Fuson. The Systematic Identification of Organic Compounds. A Laboratory Manual. 2nd ed. New York: John Wiley & Sons, 1940.
    van Arkel, A.E. and H.G.S. Snijder. Leerboek Der Scheikunde. Gegrond Op Atoommodel En Periodiek Systeem. Eerste Deel. Groningen: P. Noordhoff, 1936.
    van den Heuvel Rijnders, H. Leerboek Der Algebra, Derde Deel. Uitgave B. Zutphen: W.J. Thieme, 1937.
    van Thijn, A. Leerboek Der Vlakke Driehoeksmeting: Met Vraagstukken. Groningen: J.B. Wolters, 1939.
    Versluys, J. Vlakke Driehoeksmeting: Met Vraagstukken. Groningen: P. Noordhoff, 1932.
  - thesis, 1949 (Box 104)
    Loeb, Arthur L. An Interionic Attraction Theory For Regions of Solutions Near Phase Boundaries and An Analysis of Langmuir’s Theory Of Repulsion Between High Potential Surfaces In A Solution. Thesis, Harvard University, 1949 [bound typescript].